Guide to the Center for International Policy Records, 1960-2016 and undated; 1960-ongoing RL.00205
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Center for International Policy records
1960-2020 and undated; 1960-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Center for International Policy (Washington, D.C.)
RL.00205
60 Linear Feet
Non-profit organization founded in 1975, based in Washington, DC, whose chief focus is promoting changes in U.S. foreign and military policy in support of global human rights. The records of the Center for International Policy (CIP) span the years 1960 to 2016, and document in detail the organization's global activities in support of human rights as well as its internal administration, funding, and public relations outreach. CIP's chief areas of interest lie in United States foreign and military policies, including the activities of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA); topics cover human rights issues, U.S. relations with Central and South America, demilitarization, nuclear weapons, the Cuban trade embargo, money laundering and other aspects of international finance, terrorism, and the narcotics trade. The bulk of the files take the form of administrative files and records which contain correspondence, memos, data, reports, travel documents, and extensive files on other organizations; there are also many files of printed materials such as pamphlets, newsletters, and press releases.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Center for International Policy Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2005, 2013, and 2015.
Historical Note
The Center for International Policy (CIP), a non-governmental non-profit organization, was founded in 1975 primarily in response to the Vietnam War, and is currently (2007) based in Washington D.C. Its mission is to reform the activities of United States foreign and military policies in support of human rights in all countries. The records housed at Duke correspond to three important CIP associates: Robert White, Adam Issacson and Selig Harrison.
Robert White was hired as president of the Center for International Policy (CIP) in 1989 and served until his death in 2015. Prior to joining the CIP, White spent twenty-five years in the Foreign Service, specializing in Latin American affairs with a particular emphasis on Central America. Among the posts he held were Latin America Director of the Peace Corps, Deputy Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States, Ambassador to Paraguay and to El Salvador. After retiring from the Foreign Service in 1981, White served as a Senior Associate at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. During his tenure at the CIP, he presided at conferences and led delegations to several Latin American and Caribbean countries, published numerous studies of U.S. policy toward the region, and led an ongoing effort to reform U.S. intelligence agencies.
The CIP's Programs Director, Adam Isacson, was hired as program director for the Colombia and Demilitarization of Latin American program in 1995. Prior to that he worked for the Arias Foundation for Peace and Human Progress in San José, Costa Rica. Mr. Isacson has worked on Latin American security issues, particularly U.S. policy toward Central America and Colombia. He has been to Colombia more than twenty-five times and visited thirteen of the country's thirty-two departments.
The CIP's director of the Asia Project, Selig Harrison, is a senior scholar of the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars and director of the Century Foundation's Program on the United States and the Future of Korea. He has specialized in South Asia and East Asia for fifty years as a journalist and scholar, including as a South Asia correspondent of the Associated Press. Selig Harrison became one of the first Americans to visit North Korea since the Korean War and to interview Kim Il Sung in 1972.
Collection Overview
The records of the Center for International Policy (CIP) span the years 1960 to 2016, and document in detail the organization's global activities in support of human rights as well as its internal administration, funding, and public relations outreach. CIP's chief areas of interest lie in documenting and reforming United States foreign and military policies, including the activities of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA). Specific topics covered by materials in the collection include U.S. relations with Central and South America, particularly with Colombia, El Salvador, Haiti, and Cuba; U.S. relations with South and East Asia, particularly the Korean Peninsula; demilitarization in areas of conflict; nuclear weapons and the arms race; the Cuban trade embargo; money laundering and other aspects of international finance; terrorism in various countries; and the narcotics trade. The bulk of the files take the form of administrative files and records on other organizations which contain correspondence, memos, data, reports, travel documents, and extensive files; there are also many files containing printed materials such as pamphlets, newsletters, and press releases.
The CIP records are arranged in the following series: Development Files Series; Printed Materials Series; Oversize Materials Series; Robert White Papers Series; Adam Isacson Papers Series; Selig Harrison Papers Series; Wayne S. Smith Papers Series; Geographic, Subject, and Program Files Series; and Audiovisual Materials Series.
White's and Isacson's files retain their original arrangement into groups such as correspondence (some in digital form), research and subject files, speeches, and travel documentation. Harrison's files retain their original arrangment by region, such South and West Asia, East Asia and North Korea, while some materials have been removed to the Nuclear and Energy Subseries. The research files claim the largest proportion of the files for all individuals, and contain documentation on other organizations, individuals, and extensive information in particular on Central and South America and Asia. Other countries represented in the collection files to a lesser extent include Russia, Israel, Cuba and other countries surrounding the South and East Asia regions. Correspondence files are present throughout the collection, and include key individuals such as Iowa Senator Tom Harkin; Peter Dale Scott, former Canadian ambassador and political commentator; and Harrison Selig, Director of the Asia Program. Many other well-known politicians and activists are represented in smaller folders of materials; there are also a small number of administrative files related to internal staff members and board members. The development files reveal the nature of the CIP's fundraising activities, and the extent of support from charitable organizations; the most extensive files belong to the Ford Foundation, General Service Foundation, International Center for Development Policy, and the MacArthur Foundation; smaller files represent many other similar institutions.
Collection acquired as part of the Human Rights Archive.
Cuba -- Foreign economic relations -- United States; East Asia -- International economic relations; El Salvador -- Politics and government; Transnational crime; Central America -- Relations -- United States; Colombia -- Politics and government; Cuba -- Politics and government; South Asia -- World politics; South Asia -- Terrorism; United States -- Foreign policy; United States. Central Intelligence Agency; United States -- Relations -- Latin America; United States -- Military policy; War on Terrorism, 2001-2009; Haiti -- Politics and government; Korean War, 1950-1953; Korea (North) -- Nuclear weapons; Korea (North) -- Agriculture; South America -- Politics and government; Latin America -- Relations -- United States; South Asia -- International economic relations; South America -- Relations -- United States; Energy development -- Asia; Energy policy -- Asia; Human Rights; Human Rights -- Government policy -- United States; Intelligence service; International finance; Iraq War, 2003-2011; Korean reunification question (1945-); Terrorism; Nuclear arms control; Non-governmental organizations; Money laundering; Military policy -- United States; Drug traffic; Economic development; Economic sanctions, American -- Cuba; Isacson, Adam; White, Robert E. 1926-; Harrison, Selig S.; Human Rights Archive (Duke University); Center for International Policy (Washington, D.C.)
- Development Files, 1976-2005, 9 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains papers relating to development and funding at the Center for International Policy. The papers take two forms: grant proposals addressed to the various donors of the Center, or subject files detailing the work of the various programs at the Center with materials used in the grant writing process. Typically the documents were written by a number of staff members within the office. Organized alphabetically by name.
  - ARCA Foundation, 1987-2000, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Babcock CUISA, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Back Foundation, 1978-2002 (Box 1)
  - Baker Trust, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Beidler Charitable Trust, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Block Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
  - Boehm Foundation, 1994-1998 (Box 1)
  - Boston Foundation, 1987-2000 (Box 1)
  - Brady Fund, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Bread and Roses Communication Fund, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - Bydale Foundation, 1985-1997 (Box 1)
  - Careth Foundation, 1986-2003, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1993-2003 (Box 1)
  - Carnegie Project Proposal, 1977-1982 (Box 2)
  - Carthage Foundation, 1994-1998 (Box 2)
  - C.I.A. Proposal (3 folders), 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Columbia Foundation, 1978-1998 (Box 2)
  - Compton Foundation (4 folders), 1985-2003 (Box 2)
  - Cowell (2 folders), 1994-2000 (Box 2)
  - C. S. Foundation (3 folders), 1981-2002 (Box 2)
  - Cuba Proposal, 1996-2004 (Box 2)
  - Cudahy Fund (2 folders), 1991-1996 (Box 3)
  - Deer Creek Foundation (2 folders), 1988-1998 (Box 3)
  - Dunfey Foundation (2 folders), 1988 (Box 3)
  - Egrants.org, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
  - European Human Rights Foundation, 1982-1984 (Box 3)
  - Financial statements, 1993-1995 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation (7 folders), 1983-2004 (Box 3)
  - Funding Exchange, 1982-1997 (Box 3)
  - General Service Foundation (2 folders), 1991-2003 (Box 3)
  - General Service Foundation (3 folders), 1991-2003 (Box 4)
  - Haiti proposal, 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - H. K. H. Foundation (2 folders), 1986-2001 (Box 4)
  - Henry Jackson Foundation, 1997 (Box 4)
  - International Center for Development Policy correspondence (3 folders), 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - International Center for Development Policy proposals (1-2 of 4 folders), 1982-1992 (Box 4)
  - International Center for Development Policy proposals (3-4 of 4 folders), 1982-1992 (Box 5)
  - James Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 5)
  - Kendall Foundation, 1993-2000 (Box 5)
  - Kunstadler Family Foundation, 1993-1997 (Box 5)
  - Levinson Foundation, 1988-2004 (Box 5)
  - MacArthur Foundation (7 folders), 1994-2001 (Box 5)
  - Management Assistance Group, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Marpath Foundation, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Maryknoll Fathers and Brothers, 1988-1992 (Box 5)
  - Merck Fund (1 of 2 folders), 1993-2003 (Box 5)
  - Merck Fund (2 of 2 folders), 1993-2003 (Box 6)
  - McIntosh Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 6)
  - Mertz-Gilmore Foundation (2 folders), 1986-2000 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous funding, 1990-2003 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous proposals (2 folders), 1990-2005 (Box 6)
  - Mott Charitable Trust, 1997-2005 (Box 6)
  - Mott Fund (3 folders), 1987-1998 (Box 6)
  - National Lawyers Guild Fund, 2005 (Box 6)
  - New Prospect Foundation, 1991 (Box 6)
  - New World Foundation, 1982-1996 (Box 6)
  - New York Community Trust, 1989-2005 (Box 6)
  - Ottinger Foundation (2 folders), 1986-1998 (Box 6)
  - Peace Development Fund (2 folders), 1985-1993 (Box 6)
  - Penn Foundation, 1987-1992 (Box 6)
  - Ploughshare Fund (1 of 2 folders), 1993-2004 (Box 6)
  - Ploughshare Fund (2 of 2 folders), 1993-2004 (Box 7)
  - Public Welfare Foundation, 1993-2002 (Box 7)
  - Reebok Foundation, 1994-1996 (Box 7)
  - Reicken Foundation, 2000-2004 (Box 7)
  - Reynolds Foundation (2 folders), 1994-2000 (Box 7)
  - Smith Richardson Foundation, 2000-2002 (Box 7)
  - Rockefeller Foundation (2 folders), 1980-2003 (Box 7)
  - Rowntree Trust, 1982-2001 (Box 7)
  - Rubin Foundation (2 folders), 1982-2003 (Box 7)
  - Schumann Foundation, 1991-1993 (Box 7)
  - Shalan Foundation, 1977-1987 (Box 7)
  - Smith Family Foundation, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
  - Soros Foundation (3 folders), 1997-2000 (Box 8)
  - Sherritt International, 1998 (Box 8)
  - Sunflower Foundation, 1984-1994 (Box 8)
  - Threshold Foundation, 1995-1998 (Box 8)
  - Tides Foundation (2 folders), 1986-1996 (Box 8)
  - Town Creek Foundation, 1992-1998 (Box 8)
  - Veatch Program (3 folders), 1976-1994 (Box 8)
  - Westheimer Family Fund, 2000-2001 (Box 8)
  - Winston Foundation (1 of 4 folders), 1986-2000 (Box 8)
  - Winston Foundation (3 of 4 folders), 1986-2000 (Box 9)
- Printed Materials, 1975-2020; 1975-ongoing, 3 boxes
  Collection of printed materials relating to the Center for International Policy include press releases (which mention CIP or a staff member), International Policy Reports (published by CIP), and various articles written by staff members. Materials are arranged alphabetically by author's last name or subject.
  - Aid Memo (2 folders), 1981 Apr.-1987 July 20 (Box 21)
  - Ball, Nicole, 2002 (Box 21)
  - Eisendrath, Craig, 1999 Nov.-2000 July 26 and undated (Box 21)
  - Goodfellow, William, 1980 June-1997 Jan.4 (Box 21)
  - Goodman, Melvin, 1995 Oct. 24-2002 Aug. 20, and undated (Box 21)
  - Harrison, Selig (2 folders), 1987 July 27-2005 May 10, and undated (Box 21)
  - International Policy Report (3 folders), 1975 Dec.-2005 May (Box 21)
  - International Policy Report (4 folders), 1975 Dec.-2005 May (Box 24)
  - Isacson, Adam, 1996 Oct. 11-2002 Apr. 19, and undated (Box 24)
  - Landau, Anya, 2002 Feb. 8-July 12 (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous printed material (3 folders), 1978-2005 Dec., and undated (Box 24)
  - Morrell, James, 1979 Nov. 23-2002 Apr., and undated (Box 24)
  - Press clippings (1-2 of 6 folders), 1978 Dec. 29-2005 Apr. 18, and undated (Box 24)
  - Press clippings (3-6 of 6 folders), 1978 Dec. 29-2005 Apr. 18, and undated (Box 23)
  - Publication list, 2002 (Box 23)
  - Report to supporters, 1999-2005 (Box 23)
  - Smith, Wayne, 1992 Aug. 25-2001 Aug. 28, and undated (Box 23)
  - Web-page print-out, 2002 Feb. 26 (Box 23)
  - White, Robert, 1980 Aug. 18-2002 Sept. 27, and undated (Box 23)
  - Vaicius, Ingrid, 2002 May (Box 23)
  - Center for International Policy website, 2011-2020; 2011-ongoing
    - Subsections of Center for International Policy website, 2011-2020; 2011-ongoing
  - Center for International Policy Facebook Page, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
  - Center for International Policy Twitter account, 2012-2020; 2012-ongoing
- Robert White Papers, 1971-2014
  Contains the working files created by Robert White, a president of the Center for International Policy. White was hired as president of the Center for International Policy (CIP) in 1989, a position he held until his death in 2015. During his tenure at the CIP, he presided at conferences and led delegations to several Latin American and Caribbean countries, published numerous studies of U.S. policy toward the region, and led an ongoing effort to reform U.S. intelligence agencies. White's files are divided into five subseries: Correspondence, People, Speeches, Subject Files, and Travel White's files are divided into five subseries: Correspondence, People, Speeches, Subject Files, and Travel.
  - Correspondence, 1979-2002 and undated, 5 folders
    Most of the correspondence is addressed to White from various authors, and is business related. Files are arranged chronologically. Two folders entitled "V.I.P. letters" contain correspondence from high-ranking politicians, including Henry Kissinger, Senator John Kerry, and President Ronald Reagan; these letters are arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - 1989-2002 (3 folders) 1999-2002 (Box 9)
    - V.I.P. letters (2 folders) 1979-2001 and undated (Box 9)
    - Outgoing and miscellaneous mail, 1970s-2005; 3 folders (Box 106)
  - People, 1973-2004, 3 boxes
    Contains research files collected by White on various individuals; arranged alphabetically by last name.
    - Abrams, Elliot, 1986-1993 (Box 9)
    - Aronson, Bernard, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Barnes, Michael, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Biden, Joseph, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Carter, Jimmy, 1980-1991 (Box 9)
    - Chang, George, 1975-1991 (Box 9)
    - Cheek, James, 1991 (Box 10)
    - Clinton, Bill, 1992 (Box 10)
    - Christopher, Warren, 1993-1994 (Box 10)
    - D'Aubuisson, Roberto, 1983-1992 (Box 10)
    - D'Aubuisson, Roberto (Box 44)
    - De la Roche, Nohra, 1994 (Box 10)
    - Eisendrath, Craig, 1999-2002 (Box 10)
    - Ellacuria, Ignacio, 1990 (Box 10)
    - Forti, Alfredo, 1990 (Box 10)
    - Fujimori, Alberto, 1990 (Box 10)
    - Genovese, Bruna, 1998-2004 (Box 10)
    - Gephardt, Richard, 1990 (Box 10)
    - Guldin, Bob, 1999 (Box 10)
    - Harkin, Tom (3 folders), 1991-1995 (Box 10)
    - Harkin, Tom (Box 44)
    - Harrison, Selig, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Kennedy, Edward, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1973-1984 (Box 11)
    - Marcos, Juan Manuel, 1983 (Box 11)
    - MacMichael, David, 1990-1993 (Box 11)
    - Mills, Raymond, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Morrell, James, 2002 (Box 11)
    - Mullins, James, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Payne, Karen, 1980-1992 (Box 11)
    - Romero, Oscar, 1980-1991 (Box 11)
    - Sack, Paul, 1991 (Box 11)
    - Sanchez, Elizardo, 2001 (Box 11)
    - Schneider, Claudine, 1992 (Box 11)
    - Scott, Peter Dale (3 folders), 1986-1988 (Box 11)
    - Serrano, Alejandro, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
    - Stein, Jeff, 2001 (Box 11)
  - Speeches, 1980-2000, 4 folders
    This section contains final versions, often typed notes or transcripts, of speeches given by White on a variety of subjects. They are arranged chronologically. Also included are 2 folders containing official transcripts of testimony given by White before various government hearings and panels.
    - 1980-2000, and undated (2 folders) 1980-2000 (Box 11)
    - Testimony (2 folders), 1981-1991 (Box 11)
  - Subject Files, 1971-2004 and undated, 11 boxes
    Contains Robert White's research files, comprising the bulk of his papers. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Afghanistan, 1980-1989 (Box 12)
    - Afghanistan (Box 44)
    - Articles in Spanish, 1980-1998 (Box 12)
    - Articles in Spanish (Box 44)
    - Armenia/Azerbaijan, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Arms Industry, 1999 (Box 12)
    - Arms Trade News, 1995 (Box 12)
    - Belize, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Board of Directors, 1997-2003 (Box 12)
    - Break-In, 1986 Nov. 29 (Box 12)
    - Break-in (Box 44)
    - Burma, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
    - Cambodia, 1992 (Box 12)
    - CANF Lawsuit, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Central America (1-7 of 9 folders), 1977-1991 and undated (Box 12)
    - Central America (8-9 of 9 folders) 1977-1991 and undated (Box 13)
    - Central America (Box 44)
    - Central America-US Relations, 1971-1991 (Box 13)
    - Central American Dialogue, 1995-1996 (Box 13)
    - Chile - Congressional testimony, 1987 (Box 13)
    - China, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Church (2 folders), 1971-1991 (Box 13)
    - Church (Box 44)
    - C.I.A. (4 folders), 1982-2001 (Box 13)
    - CIA (Box 44)
    - Contemporary Marxism, 1981 (Box 14)
    - Costa Rica, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Cuba (3 folders), 1997-2002 (Box 14)
    - Cuba: African-American journalist delegation (Box 44)
    - African American Journalist Delegation, 2001 (Box 14)
    - Drugs - Articles (2 folders), 1986-1993 (Box 14)
    - Drugs - Testimony, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Drugs - CRS briefs, 1988-1990 (Box 14)
    - Drugs - GAO reports, 1987-1991 (Box 14)
    - Drugs - Money laundering / dirty money, 1989-2000s (Box 14, Box 106)
    - El Salvador (1-11 of 13 folders), 1976-1981 (Box 15)
    - El Salvador (12-13 of 13 folders), 1981 (Box 16)
    - El Salvador - Church Women Murders (2 folders), 1981 (Box 16)
    - El Salvador - Ford v. Garcia, 2000 (Box 16)
    - El Salvador - Military Strategy Assistance Team (2 folders), 1981 (Box 16)
    - El Salvador, 1980s-1993 (Box 106)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes White's manuscript notebook re: FMLN "Negotiations and How to Get There," (1988); general reports and photocopies re: El Salvador and military terrorism; and a copy of Letter from UN Sec. General to Security Council President (1993).
    - El Salvador (Box 44)
    - Enterprise for America, 1990 (Box 16)
    - F.B.I. (1-4 of 8 folders), 1982-1986 (Box 16)
    - F.B.I. (5-8 of 8 folders), 1988-1991 (Box 17)
    - Foreign agents, 1987 (Box 17)
    - Foreign policy, 1974-1993 (Box 17)
    - Foreign policy (Box 44)
    - Grenada, 1983 (Box 17)
    - Grenada (Box 44)
    - Guatemala, 1981-1994 (Box 17)
    - Haiti, 1992-2000s (Box 18, Box 106, Box 17)
    - Haiti - Amnesty International, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Aristide visit, 1992 Mar. 16-19 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Briefing, 1993 (Box 18)
    - Haiti- Bush administration policy, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Congressional delegation trip, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Consultation, 1994 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Eight Points of Clinton, 2001 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - House Subcommittee hearing materials (2 folders), 1992 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Letters, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Memos to OAS, US Embassy, 1991 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Our Man in Haiti, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Projected Haiti trip, 1992 (Box 18)
    - Haiti - Telephone numbers, undated (Box 18)
    - (Haiti) Testimony and Notes, 1992 (Box 19)
    - Haiti (Box 44)
    - Harvard, 1986 (Box 19)
    - Hearings (2 folders), 1981-1991 (Box 19)
    - Honduras, 1980s-2000s (Box 19, Box 106)
    - Honduras (Box 44)
    - Human rights (2 folders), 1973-1995 (Box 19)
    - Human rights speeches by misc., 1988-1993 (Box 19)
    - Ireland Commission, 1987-1990 (Box 19)
    - Kissinger Commission, 1983-1984 (Box 19)
    - Kissinger Commission (Box 44)
    - LASA, 1991-1994 (Box 19)
    - Latin America (2 folders), 1981-1991 (Box 19)
    - Latin America (Box 44)
    - Lome VI Convention, 1990-1992 (Box 19)
    - Notes (1 of 2 folders), undated (Box 19)
    - Notes (2 of 2 folders), undated (Box 20)
    - Name resources, 2000 (Box 20)
    - National Enquirer debacle, 1998 (Box 20)
    - National Security - Outerspace Conference - Pakistan Meeting, 2002 (Box 20)
    - National Security - Outerspace Conference - Palestine-Israeli Meeting, 2001 (Box 20)
    - National Security - Outerspace Conference - Shield of Dreams, 2001 (Box 20)
    - OAS Conference (2 folders), 1976 (Box 20)
    - Operation Condor (2 folders), 1976-2004 (Box 20)
    - Organizations supporting AJS, 2004 (Box 20)
    - Personal, 1977-1993 (Box 20)
    - Press clippings (Box 44)
    - PR campaign, 1984 (Box 20)
    - Sohn Human Rights Award, 2002 (Box 20)
    - South Korea, 1985 (Box 20)
    - South Korea (Box 44)
    - Sign-on letters, 1999-2002 (Box 20)
    - Terrorism, 1979-1987 (Box 20)
    - U.S. Institute of Peace, undated (Box 20)
    - Carranza trial articles, 2005 (Box 106)
    - Cold War, 2002-2005 (Box 106)
    - Queen of the Mosquito / Mesquiet Indians, 1969 (Box 94)
    - Colombia, 2000s (Box 106, Box 94)
    - Foro Nacional de Conservacion, 2000s (Box 106)
    - Free Trade, 2000s (Box 106)
    - Fundacion para el Desarrollo Empresarial Rural (Funder), 2003 (Box 106)
    - Gangs / UN, 2000s (Box 106)
    - FOIA Requests (Box 94)
    - Oral history interview transcript, Georgetown University Foreign Affairs Oral History Program, 1992 (Box 94)
  - Travel, 1988-2004, 8 folders